Guide to the Research Institute for the Study of Man (RISM) Vertical Files RISM.VF.1
New York University Archives
- Caribbean Area
  - Caribbean Area: Corporations, Foreign (Box 4)
    - Industrialization and the Role of the Multinational Corporations in the Caribbean, 1981; RISM 17559; Ashley, Paul W.; p. 49-74. (Box 4)
      Caribbean Area.; Corporations, International.
  - Caribbean Area: Cotton (Box 4)
    - Report of the West Indian Sea Island Cotton Association Incorporated, 1953-1954; RISM 17689; West Indian Sea Island Cotton Association; 2 items; 1953, 1954; no content (Box 4)
      Caribbean Area.; Cotton.
  - Caribbean Area: Creole Dialects, Bibliography (Box 4)
    - Bibliographical Research: A Bibliography of Caribbean Creole Languages, \1963; RISM 20225; Rubin, Joan; p. 51-52. (Box 4)
      Bibliography.; Caribbean Area.; Creole dialects.
    - Bibliographical Research: Towards a Bibliography of Works Dealing with the Creole Languages of the Caribbean Area, Louisiana, and the Guianas, 1963; RISM 20226; Dillard, J. L. (Joey Lee), 1924-; p. 84-95. (Box 4)
      Creole dialects.; Bibliography.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Creole Dialects, English (Box 4)
    - "Whagta Kriowday!": West Indian Creoles in 'Finnegan's Wake', undated; RISM 17170; Reisman, Karl; 9 pages (Box 4)
      Caribbean Area.; Creole dialects, English.
    - Standard and Non-Standard Language Attitudes in a Creole Continuum, 1983; RISM 17695; Rickford, John R., 1949-; 27 pages (Box 4)
    - The Linguistic Continuity of Africa in the Caribbean, 1970; RISM 17765; Alleyne, Mervyn C.; p. 3-16 (Box 4)
    - Some Early Indications of Learning a Second Dialect, 1967; RISM 17766; Craig, Dennis R.; p. 133-140 (Box 4)
    - Teaching Trinidadian(s) English, 1966; RISM 17764; Borely, Clive B.; p. 1-6 (Box 4)
  - Caribbean Area: Cricket (Box 4)
    - Cricket: How to Play the Game, undated; RISM 20227; 7 pages (Box 4)
      Caribbean Area.; Cricket.
    - Cricket and the Artistic Tradition: West Indian Cricket as a Performing Art, 1998; RISM 25168; Nettleford, Rex M., 1933-2010; p. 82-99. (Box 4)
    - Celebrating Cricket: The Symbolic Construction of Caribbean Politics, 1981; Manning, Frank E. (Box 4)
      Cricket.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Crime and Criminals (Box 4)
    - Report for the Commonwealth Caribbean Conference on the Prevention of Crime and the Treatment of Offenders, 1975; RISM 17786; 18 pages (Box 4)
      Caribbean Area.; Crime and criminals
    - CARICRIMA III: Caribbean Crime Conference, 1980, RISM 24309; Caribbean Association of Criminology (3rd:1980: Runaway Bay, Jamaica); 4 pages (Box 4)
    - Lester Bird Responds to Privy Council Decision, 2002; RISM 26918; 1 page; 1p. (Box 4)
  - Caribbean Area: Cultural Pluralism (Box 4)
    - Ethnic and Cultural Pluralism in the British Caribbean, 1957; RISM 17644; Smith, M. G. (Michael Garfield); 9 pages (Box 4)
      Caribbean Area.; Cultural pluralism.
    - Perception as a Factor in the Configuration of Caribbean Social Space, 1984; RISM 23340; Thomas-Hope, Elizabeth M.; 22 pages (Box 4)
    - The Range and Variation of Caribbean Societies, 1960; RISM 24134; Lowenthal, David; p. 786-795. (Box 4)
    - The Plural Society Debate: Some Comments on a Recent Contribution, 1966; RISM 24150; McKenzie, H. I.; p. 53-60. (Box 4)
    - Cultural Difference and Social Assortment in the Caribbean Region, undated; RISM 25159; Mintz, Sidney W. (Sidney Wilfred), 1922-2015; p. 14-27. (Box 4)
      Cultural pluralism.; Caribbean Area.
    - Duas Variantes das Relacoes Raciais No Caribe, 1995; RISM 25160; Price, Richard; p. 185-201. (Box 4)
  - Caribbean Area: Cultural Relations (Box 4)
    - Procesos Etnoculturales y Percepciones Mutuas en el Desarrollo de la Relaciones entre el Caribe de Habla Inglesa y America Latina, 1984; RISM 17642; Serbín, Andr‌és; 2 items (Box 4)
      Caribbean Area.; Cultural relations.
    - Problems of Intercultural Communication in the Caribbean, 1982; RISM 17647; Perusse, Roland I.; 12 pages (Box 4)
      Cultural relations.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Culture (Box 4)
    - The Declaration of Santo Domingo; Adopted by Meeting of Experts on Caribbean Cultures, convened by UNESCO, 1978; RISM 17639; 16 pages (Box 4)
      Caribbean Area.; Culture.
    - The Ethnic and Colonial Heritage of the Caribbean: "Ten Commandments", undated; RISM 17811; Lewis, Gordon K.; 11 pages (Box 4)
      Culture.; Caribbean Area.
    - Caribbean Cultural Values: Implications for Caribbean Social Life, undated; RISM 17812; Nettleford, Rex M., 1933-2010; 12 pages (Box 4)
    - Report on Caribbean Culture and Conservation Conference, udnated; RISM 17813; Elder, J. D. (Jacob Delworth), 1913-2003; 13 pages (Box 4)
    - United States Cultural Influences on the English-Speaking Caribbean During the Twentieth Century, 1983; RISM 17814; Knight, Franklin W.; 23 pages (Box 4)
    - Reflections on Rex Nettleford's "Caribbean Cultural Identity", 1979; RISM 24254; Sherlock, Philip Manderson, Sir; p. 41-56. (Box 4)
  - Caribbean Area: Description and Travel (1 of 2) (Box 4)
    - Fact Sheets on the UK Dependencies; Bermuda, British Guiana, British Honduras, Jamaica, 1959; RISM 17336; Great Britain. Central Office of Information; various paging. (Box 4)
    - The Caribbean: Sun, Sea, and Seething, 1981; RISM 17337; Grove, Noel; p. 244-272. (Box 4)
    - A Fresh Breeze Stirs the Leewards, 1966; RISM 17338; Mitchell, Carleton, 1910-2007; p. 488-537. (Box 4)
    - The Caribbean: A Geography Note-Book, 1962; RISM 17340; Whybrow, S. J. R.; 31 pages (Box 4)
    - Executive Escapes: The Atlantic's Guide to Winter "Get Away" Vacation Spots, 1983; RISM 17341; Showker, Kay; p. 1-14. (Box 4)
    - How I Stopped Worrying and Learned to Love the Caribbean, 1976; RISM 17342; Blumenthal, Ralph; p. 33-43, 72-89. (Box 4)
    - Jamaica, Trinidad and Tobago, Dominican Republic, 1980; RISM 17343; Stagg, Camille J., 1942-; p. 6-16. (Box 4)
    - The West Indies; Prepared for the American Oxford Encyclopedia, 1960; RISM 17344; Rubin, Vera D.; 7 pages (Box 4)
    - The Peoples and Cultures of the Caribbean Area, 1962; RISM 17346; Simpson, George Eaton, 1904-1998; p. 240-258. (Box 4)
    - The West Indies, 1958, RISM 17347; Great Britain. Civil Service Preparatory Commission; 36 pages (Box 4)
    - A Pocket Guide to the Caribbean, 1977; RISM 17349; United States. Department of Defense; 78 pages (Box 4)
    - Enkele Sociaal-Geografische Kenmerken van het Caribische Gebied, undated; RISM 17350; Hoetink, H.; p. 145-156. (Box 4)
    - The West Indies; A Special SR Fall Travel Section, 1968; RISM 17352; Sutton, Horace; p. 43-109. (Box 4)
    - As Others See Us, No. 5: Physical Features, Flora & Fauna, undated; RISM 20189; University of the West Indies (Mona, Jamaica). University Radio Service; 7 pages (Box 4)
  - Caribbean Area: Description and Travel (2 of 2) (Box 4)
    - British West Indian Interlude, 1941; RISM 24114; Langley, Anne Rainey; 46 pages; p. 1-46 (Box 4)
    - Carib Cruises the West Indies, 1948; RISM 24180; Mitchell, Carleton, 1910-2007; p. 1-56. (Box 4)
    - West Indies, 1960; RISM 24137; Lowenthal, David; p. 473-476. (Box 4)
    - Caribbean Vacations: Island Hoppin', Stoppin', Shoppin', 1965 (Box 4)
    - Where to Play in the Caribbean, British West Indian Airways (Box 4)
    - Caribbean Vacationlands Vol. V: "To See and Do in the Caribbean", 1955; 129 pages (Box 4)
    - 5 Caribbean Cruises to West Indies and South American on the S.S. IIe de France from New York, 1955 (Box 4)
    - West Indies and Gulf Coasts; Longmans Colour Geographies, 1955; 40 pages (Box 4)
    - The Conch Republic! Key West, Florida's Caribbean, 1991; 8 pages (Box 4)
    - Cue Magazine, New York's Only Complete Entertainment Weekly; Travel in the Caribbean, May 1955; 48 pages (Box 4)
    - 7 Tropical Cruises, Winter Season 1955-1956; S.S. Patricia, Queen of the Swedish Lloyd to the West Indies South America, Panama Canal (Box 4)
  - Caribbean Area: Drug Abuse (Box 4)
    - Drug Abuse in the Caribbean: Report of the Drug Seminar Held in Trinidad, 1986, 1987; RISM 17887; 52 pages (Box 4)
      Drug abuse.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Drug Trade, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Caribbean Area: Drug Traffic (Box 4)
    - Between Rocks and a Hard Place: The "Shiprider Controversy" and the Question of Caribbean Sovereignty, 1998; RISM 25217; Henke, Holger W.; p. 425-437. (Box 4)
      Drug traffic.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: East Indians (Box 4)
    - Hindu Marriage in the Caribbean, 2000; RISM 18062; Samaroo, Brinsley; 4 pages (Box 4)
      Caribbean Area.; East Indians.
    - "In Sick Longing for the Further Shore": Return Migration by Caribbean East Indians in the 19th and 20th Centuries, 1980; RISM 18063; Samaroo, Brinsley; 21 pages (Box 4)
    - The East Indian Family Oversees, 1964; RISM 18065; Davids, Leo; p. 383-396. (Box 4)
    - East Indians and the Federation of the British West Indies, 1961; RISM 18066; Proctor, J. Harris (Jesse Harris); p. 370-395. (Box 4)
    - Migration and Social Change: Survey of Indian Communities Oversees, 1968; RISM 18067; Jayawardena, Chandra; p. 426-449. (Box 4)
    - East Indian Influences in the British Caribbean, 1984; RISM 18068; Samaroo, Brinsley; 18 pages (Box 4)
    - History, Ecology, and Demography in the British Caribbean: An Analysis of East Indian Ethnicity, 1971; RISM 18064; Ehrlich, Allen S.; p. 166-180. (Box 4)
  - Caribbean Area: Ecology (Box 5)
    - The Destabilization of the Caribbean Environment: Impact and Aftermath, 1977; RISM 17905; Richardson, Bonham C., 1939-; 13 pages (Box 5)
      Caribbean Area.; Ecology.
    - The Aftermath of Development: Environmental Deterioration and Livelihood Uncertainty in the Eastern Caribbean, 1981; RISM 17906; Richardson, Bonham C., 1939-; 8 pages (Box 5)
      Ecology.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Economic Assistance (Box 5)
    - Pattern of Government Expenditure in Grant-Aided Territories in the Caribbean, undated; RISM 11839; McIntyre, Alister; 7 pages; 7.0 (Box 5)
      Economic assistance.; Caribbean Area.
    - Project Report: Eastern Caribbean, 1985; RISM 17919; Oxfam America; 1 page (Box 5)
    - Some Thoughts on Economic Aid to Developing Countries; Address to the Economics Society of the University of the West Indies, Jamaica, 1963; RISM 17927; Williams, Eric Eustace, 1911-1981; 28 pages (Box 5)
  - Caribbean Area: Economic Conditions (1 of 2) (Box 5)
    - New World Occasional Bulletin No. 2; Speaking Painfully, 1967; RISM 15679; 12 pages (Box 5)
      Economic conditions.; Caribbean Area.; America.
    - British West Indian Economic History in Imperial Perspective, 1939; RISM 17211; Shephard, C. Y. (Cecil Yaxley); p. 151-155, 175-178. (Box 5)
      Economic conditions.; Caribbean Area.
    - Government Policies Toward Foreign Direct Investment: Can Puerto Rico Provide Lessons for the Caribbean?, 1984; RISM 17203; Santiago, Carlos E., 1952-; 20 pages (Box 5)
    - A Nation Divided: Quest for Caribbean Integration, 1991; RISM 17708; Will, W. Marvin; p. 3-37. (Box 5)
    - Aspects of the Problem of Metropolitan Influence and Dependence in the Caribbean, 1981; RISM 16965; Watson, Hilbourne A., 1943-; p. 29-48. (Box 5)
      Caribbean Area.; Economic conditions.
    - British Possessions: The Impact of World War II, 1943; RISM 26737; Williams, Eric Eustace, 1911-1981; p. 20-23. (Box 5)
    - The Economics of Everyday Life in the West Indies, 1953; RISM 17317; Williams, Gertrude; 52 pages (Box 5)
    - The Political Economy of the English Speaking Caribbean: A Summary View, 1971; RISM 17318; Demas, William G.; 22 cm. (Box 5)
    - Compulsions of Integration, 1992; RISM 17319; Lewis, Vaughan A.; 26 pages (Box 5)
    - Problems of Economic Research: Added Comments Respecting the West Indies; Bulletin No. 30, 1941; RISM 17320; Williams, Eric Eustace, 1911-1981; p. 58-67. (Box 5)
    - Country Reports: Greater Antilles; Cuba, Dominican Republic, Haiti, 1975; RISM 17322; Barclays Bank; 4 pages (Box 5)
    - Report of the Fifth Caribbean Regional Conference of the Commonwealth Parliamentary Association, 1967; RISM 17323; 5 pages (Box 5)
    - Regional Economic Committee of the British West Indies, British Guiana, and British Honduras; Bulletin No. 47, 1955; RISM 17325; Great Britain. Regional Economic Committee of the British West Indies, British Guiana, and British Honduras; 12 pages (Box 5)
    - Dangerous Period for CARICOM, February 1978; RISM 17326; Lewis, Vaughan A.; p. 5, 19. (Box 5)
    - Report from the Policy Workshop: "An Alternative Policy for Central America and the Caribbean", 1983; RISM 20190; 9 pages (Box 5)
    - Necesidad Objectiva de la Colaboracion Economica en el Caribe, 1981; RISM 20191; p. 75-97. (Box 5)
  - Caribbean Area: Economic Conditions (2 of 2) (Box 5)
    - A Measurement of Economic Growth for Selected Caribbean Nations, 1989; RISM 23170; Nissan, Edward, 1929-; p. 61-79. (Box 5)
    - A Brief Encounter with the Caribbean and Central America, 1979; RISM 23987; Davis-Trainor, Julia; 17 pages (Box 5)
    - Economic Stability in the Caribbean, 1973; RISM 24066; Hill, Anthony; 8 pages (Box 5)
    - Caribbean: Quarterly Forecast Report; Political Risk, Economic Performance and Outlook, and Key Economic Sectors, 2002; RISM 27383; 31 pages; 31.0 (Box 5)
    - Assessment of Country Credit Worthiness with Special Reference to the OECS, 1990; RISM 26361; Murphy, Elliott; 8 pages; 8.0 (Box 5)
    - The Caribbean and the World Economy: Patterns of Insertion and Contemporary Options, 1983; Stone, Carl, 1940-1993; 24 pages (Box 5)
    - West Caribbean Quarterly Forecast Report; 2003, Business Monitor International; 24 pages (Box 5)
    - East Caribbean Quarterly Forecast Report; 2003, Business Monitor International; 24 pages (Box 5)
    - The East Caribbean Business Forecast Report; 2004, Business Monitor International; 23 pages (Box 5)
    - The West Caribbean Business Forecast Report; 2004, Business Monitor International; 22 pages (Box 5)
  - Caribbean Area: Economic Development (Box 5)
    - A Brief Look at Policy-Oriented Work in Monetary Economics and Integration, 1983; RISM 17938; Persaud, Wilberne H.; 15 pages (Box 5)
      Economic development.; Caribbean Area.
    - A Disciplinary Status Report on Planning and Administration in the Caribbean, undated; RISM 17939; Lutchman, Harold A.; 13 pages (Box 5)
    - The West Indies Emergent: Problems and Prospects, 1961; RISM 17940; Springer, Hugh W.; 16 pages (Box 5)
      Caribbean Area.; Economic development.
    - Nationalism and Industrial Development in the British Caribbean, 1958; RISM 17941; Farley, Rawle, 1922-; 58 pages (Box 5)
    - Financial Constraints and Economic Development in the Commonwealth Caribbean: The Recent Experience, 1983; RISM 20229; Ramsaran, Ramesh F.; 23 pages (Box 5)
    - The Legacy of Caribbean History and Tourism, 1971; RISM 23182; Harrigan, Norwell; 14 pages (Box 5)
  - Caribbean Area: Economic Policy (Box 5)
    - The Impact of Caribbean Economic Thought on Development Policy, 1983; RISM 17204; Girvan, Norman, 1941-; 14 pages (Box 5)
      Caribbean Area.; Economic policy.
    - Caribbean Basin Integration: Pacem in Maribus, 1984; RISM 17205; Rubin, Vera D.; 8 pages (Box 5)
    - The Political Economy of Exploitation in the Caribbean, 1971-1972; RISM 17206; Thomas, Clive Yolande; p. 39-49. (Box 5)
  - Caribbean Area: Education (1 of 2) (Box 5)
    - Aims and Priorities in Education, 1956; RISM 16388; Sherlock, Philip Manderson, Sir; 6 pages (Box 5)
      Caribbean Area.; Education.
    - Reflections on Curriculum and Education in the British Caribbean, 1971; RISM 16328; Comitas, Lambros; 24 pages (Box 5)
      Education.; Caribbean Area.
    - Education in Dependent Territories in America, 1946; RISM 18005; Williams, Eric Eustace, 1911-1981; p. 534-551. (Box 5)
    - You Must Leave Us: Education, Out-Migration, and Upward Mobility in the Commonwealth Caribbean, 1983; RISM 18009; Ralston, Lenore D.; p. 51-66. (Box 5)
    - Education for Development in the Caribbean, 1971; RISM 18010; Edwards, P. A.; 15 pages (Box 5)
    - Education for Human Development, 1984; RISM 18012; Dottin, Erskine S.; 14 pages (Box 5)
    - Education and Pluralism in Selected Caribbean Societies, 1967; RISM 18015; Farrell, Joseph P.; p. 160-181. (Box 5)
    - English Language Teaching in the Commonwealth Caribbean, 1970; RISM 18014; Carrington, Lawrence D.; 8 pages (Box 5)
    - Regional Cooperation in Education, 1: The Establishment of a Caribbean Examinations Council, undated; RISM 18016; Caribbean Free Trade Association. Commonwealth Caribbean Regional Secretariat; 7 pages (Box 5)
    - Regional Cooperation in Education, 2: Scheme for Cooperation in Legal Education and Training, 1970; RISM 18017; Caribbean Free Trade Association. Commonwealth Caribbean Regional Secretariat; 13 pages (Box 5)
    - The Cost of Education: Development and Welfare in the West Indies, 1945; RISM 18021; Stanley, Oliver; 32 pages (Box 5)
    - Developing Caribbean Human Capital: An Examination of Public Spending on Education, 1984; RISM 18123; Palmer, Ransford W.; 12 pages (Box 5)
    - Chapter on Education from the West India Royal Commission (Moyne), 1938-1939, 1945; RISM 23633; Trinidad and Tobago. Ministry of Education; 28 page (Box 5)
  - Caribbean Area: Education (2 of 2) (Box 5)
    - Education and Job Opportunities in the Caribbean, 1973; RISM 23978; Cross, Malcolm; 34 pages (Box 5)
    - Some Observations on the Educational Position of the British Caribbean, 1965; RISM 24238; Roberts, G. W. (George W.); 9 pages (Box 5)
    - Call for Changes in Caribbean Education System, 1981; RISM 24784; Irvine, Dennis H.; 1 page (Box 5)
    - The Aim of Education, 1971; RISM 24785; Roach, Iris; 3 pages (Box 5)
  - Caribbean Area: Education, Bibliography (Box 5)
    - Literacy: A Key To Open Many Doors; A Select Bibliography, 1990; RISM 17986; Jamaica Library Service; 32 pages (Box 5)
      Caribbean Area.; Bibliography.; Education.
    - Library Resources for Research in Education in the Caribbean, 1971; RISM 23940; Bennett, Hazel; 16 pages (Box 5)
      Education.; Caribbean Area.; Bibliography.
  - Caribbean Area: Education, Higher (Box 5)
    - Economics Teaching in the 1980's, 1983; RISM 17908; Pantin, Dennis; 6 pages (Box 5)
      Education, Higher.; Caribbean Area.
    - APICE Seminar; Pan American Association of Educational Credit Institutions, 1975; RISM 17969; Pan-American Association of Educational Credit Institutions; 39 pages (Box 5)
    - Report of the Mission on Higher Technical Education in the British Caribbean, 1957; RISM 18006; Great Britain. Colonial Office. Mission on Higher Technical Education in the British Caribbean; 30 pages (Box 5)
    - Communications and University Teaching with Particular Reference to the Caribbean, 1971; RISM 18018; Inter-University Research Unit (Cambridge, England); 46 pages (Box 5)
    - Proceedings of the University of West Indies Small States Conference, 2000, RISM 27385; 21 pages; 21p. (Box 5)
  - Caribbean Area: Elections (Box 5)
    - The West Indies: Federal Elections, 25th March, 1958, RISM 17997; Great Britain. Civil Service Preparatory Commission; 10 pages (Box 5)
      Caribbean Area.; Elections.
  - Caribbean Area: Emigration and Immigration (Box 5)
    - Recent Caribbean Migrations: Negligible or Neglected Factor, 1984; RISM 17405; Guengant, J. P. (Jean Pierre); 66 pages (Box 5)
      Caribbean Area.; Emigration and immigration.
    - Migration and Underdevelopment: The Caribbean, 1983; RISM 17406; Rubenstein, Hymie; p. 30-32. (Box 5)
    - Caribbean Migration: Causes and Consequences, 1982; RISM 17407; Bach, Robert L.; 13 pages (Box 5)
    - West Indian Emigrants Overseas, 1976; RISM 17408; Lowenthal, David; 17 pages (Box 5)
    - Return Migration to the English-Speaking Caribbean: Review and Commentary, 1982; RISM 17409; Rubenstein, Hymie; p. 3-34. (Box 5)
    - Summary Statistics on Indenture and Associated Migration Affecting the West Indies, 1834-1918, 1966; RISM 17411; Roberts, G. W. (George W.); p. 125-134. (Box 5)
    - Internal Migration and Urbanization in the Caribbean, ca. 1982; RISM 17412; Hope, Kempe Ronald, Sr., 1949-; 15 pages (Box 5)
    - Venezuela's Role in Caribbean Basin Migrations: Recent Trends, 1982; RISM 17414; Roy, Ralph van; 26 pages (Box 5)
      Emigration and immigration.; Caribbean Area.
    - Research Proposal on the Migration Process: A Longitudinal Study of Immigrants to the U.S.A. from the Eastern Caribbean, undated; RISM 17416; Marshall, Dawn; 27 pages (Box 5)
    - Remittances and Rural Underdevelopment in the English-Speaking Caribbean, 1983; RISM 18362; Rubenstein, Hymie; p. 295-306. (Box 5)
    - The Impact of Remittances in the Rural English-Speaking Caribbean: Notes on the Literature, 1982; RISM 18363; Rubenstein, Hymie; p. 237-265. (Box 5)
    - Immigration Problems in the Americas and their Economic Impact: An Emerging Agenda for Caribbean Basin Research, ca. 1981; RISM 18365; Gómez-Samper, Henry; 11 pages (Box 5)
    - Population Flight: The Origins of the Caribbean Diaspora, 1950-1980, 1987; RISM 23337; Simmons, Alan B. (Alan Burtham), 1941-; 21 pages (Box 5)
    - West Indians Abroad: Some Comparative Perspectives, undated; RISM 24136; Lowenthal, David; 10 pages (Box 5)
  - Caribbean Area: Emigration and Immigration, Bibliography (Box 5)
    - Historical Writing on Migration into the Commonwealth Caribbean: A Bibliographic Review of the Period c.1838-c.1938, 1986; RISM 17413; Thompson, Alvin O.; p. 141-166. (Box 5)
      Caribbean Area.; Bibliography.; Emigration and immigration.
  - Caribbean Area: Festival of Creative Arts, 1972-1981 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean Area: English Language, Study and Teaching (Box 5)
    - Interim Report of Meeting on the Teaching of English, University of the West Indies, 1964, RISM 24984; University of the West Indies (Mona, Jamaica). Department of Education; 5 pages (Box 5)
      Study and teaching.; English language.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Family (Box 5)
    - Illegitimacy in the Caribbean Social Structure, 1960; RISM 18405; Goode, William J.; p. 21-30. (Box 5)
      Family.; Caribbean Area.
    - Male Attitudes in Caribbean Family Life, 1974; RISM 18406; Hodge, Merle, 1944-; 5 pages; p. 25-29. (Box 5)
    - Family, Social Change and Social Policy in the West Indies, 1982; RISM 18407; Smith, Raymond Thomas, 1925-; p. 111-142. (Box 5)
    - The Family in the Caribbean, 1960; RISM 18408; Smith, Raymond Thomas, 1925-; p. 67-75. (Box 5)
    - Household and Family in the Caribbean, 1960; RISM 18409; González, Nancie L. Solien, 1929-; p. 101-105. (Box 5)
    - An Economic Analysis of the Extended Family in the West Indies, 1971; RISM 18410; Kerton, Robert R.; p. 423-434. (Box 5)
    - The Family and the Modern World System: Some Observations from the Caribbean, 1978; RISM 18411; Smith, Raymond Thomas, 1925-; p. 337-360 (Box 5)
      Caribbean Area.; Family.
    - Gezinsvormen in het Caribisch Gebied, 1961; RISM 18413; Hoetink, H.; p. 81-93. (Box 5)
    - A Propos de la Legitimite et de la Matrifocalite: Tentative De Re-Interpretation, 1965; RISM 23647; Vall‌e, Lionel; p. 163-177. (Box 5)
    - Cultural-Historical and Structural-Functional Orientations and the Analysis of the West Indian Family, 1968; RISM 24046; Greenfield, Sidney M.; 20 pages (Box 5)
    - Culture and Social Structure in the Caribbean: Some Recent Work on Family and Kinship Studies, 1953; RISM 24260; Smith, Raymond Thomas, 1925-; p. 24-46. (Box 5)
    - Working Mothers and Absent Fathers: Family Organization in the Caribbean, 1964; RISM 23992; Du Bois, Hazel; 11 pages (Box 5)
  - Caribbean Area: Family, Bibliography (Box 5)
    - Family Life, Public Health & Related Topics: An Annotated Bibliography from the West Indian Collection at the Medical Library, University of the West Indies, 1986; RISM 18404; Mansingh, Laxmi; 40 pages (Box 5)
      Family.; Bibliography.; Caribbean Area.